Marya Annette McQuirter Collection 141
People's Archive, MLK Library
Marya Annette McQuirter Collection
1800-2005
People's Archive, MLK Library
McQuirter, Marya
141
45 Linear feet
33 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed without series.
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Marya Annette McQuirter is a scholar in African American history, in Washington, D.C. McQuirter serves as a historian at the National Museum of African American History and Culture. As a member of the staff in the Visual Arts department, she researches, and writes content for the analog and digital platforms for the Visual Arts inaugural exhibition. She works with curators to promote the life and work of artists through exhibitions. McQuirter's publications include a volume in the Young Oxford History of African Americans series. In addition to her publications, McQuirter curated an exhibit at the Martin Luther King, Jr. Memorial Library and for the "America I Am: African American Imprint" traveling exhibit with talk show host and author Tavis Smiley. McQuirter taught African American and American studies courses at George Mason University, and American University. McQuirter received her PhD in history from the University of Michigan in 2000.
Custodial History
Gift of Marya Annette McQuirter, 2006 and 2009.
Scope and Contents
The Marya Annete McQuirter papers document McQuirter's research on African American history. Documents include research, subject, and organizational files, as well as correspondence, newspaper clippings,memorabilia, photographs, and research materials pertaining to McQuirter's dissertation.
African Americans; Correspondence; Photographs; Documentation; Ephemera; Black persons
- Series 1
  - Kelly Miller Articles - 1920-1930s, 1920-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - African American Historic Site Survey: Table of Contents/List of Personnel/Criteria, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - African American Historic Site Survey: List of 100 sites/List of 200 Sites/one page studies, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - African American Historic Site Survey: List of Sites, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of 100 sites, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - African American Historic Site Survey Advisory Committee/Monthly/Quarterly/Final Reports and Project Completion, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History Workshop, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - S.N Reid Memorial Program, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Notes on Deconstructing "The Folk" by Robin D.G Kelly, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Copied Photographs - Female Superstars/Marian Anderson/Easter Egg Role, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Visual Images - Couples, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Images of Dance, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Folkore of industrial Society: Popular Culture and Its Audiences. Lawrence W. Levine, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Maps and Population Characteristics for D.C, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Photographs and Photo Request Info, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photo, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Arrests made Fiscal Year 1946 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Images of Reading, 1938-1942 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photos - The Murray Palace Casino and Oral Traditions, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Prophet of Negro History, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Letters to my Son by Deadrick F. Jenkins, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - DC Neighborhoods, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Negro Youth - Primary Articles, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Robin D.G Kelly, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Sports - Primary Articles, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - DC Historic Site Pamphlets, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The New Negro Thirty Years Afterward 16th Annual Spring Conference, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 50th Anniversary Commemoration of Thompson's Restaurant Case (1 of 4), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 50th Anniversary Commemoration of Thompson's Restaurant Case (2 of 4), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 50th Anniversary Commemoration of Thompson's Restaurant Case (3 of 4), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 50th Anniversary Commemoration of Thompson's Restaurant Case (4 of 4), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Peace/Anti-War Papers and Pamphlets (1 of 3), undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Peace/Anti-War Papers and Pamphlets (2 of 3), undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Peace/Anti-War Papers and Pamphlets (3 of 3), undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Ms. And U Tune Magazines, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - African American women's Occupational Status in Washington, 1910-1930 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Kathy Schneider - Washington at Home: An Illustrated History of Neighborhoods in the Nation's Capital, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Travel Subchapter - Chapter 6, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Negro Travel, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Chapter Two: Where is the Negro's Heaven?: Cultural and Social Geography of Washington D.C, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Businesses owned and operated by negroes in Washington D.C, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Authentic Blackness. J Martin Favor, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Handwritten Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Jeffery J. Pilz - "The Beginnings of Organized Play for Black America", 1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Library of Congress Special Search Request, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - A Bibliographic Sampler: Afro American Publishers of Afro American Religious Literature, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Children's Playgrounds in the District of Columbia 1902-1942, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Inarticulate Longings: the Ladies: Home Journal Gender and the Promises of Consumer Culture, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - From Hucklebuck to Hip Hop - John W. Roberts, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Every Grain is Standing for Itself: African American Style in the Nineteenth and Twentieth Centuries, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Negro Youth at the Crossways, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Secret Societies as Factors in the Social and Economic Life of the Negro, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Recreation in Colored Communities, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Recreation - Recreation and Amusement, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Playfields for Negro Communities, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Reaction for Colored Citizens - Needs and Methods, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Rebop, Bebop and Bop by Marshall W. Stearns, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Recreation for Colored Citizens in the New Democracy, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Fourteenth Census of the US 1920 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Another Audience: Black Moviegoing 1907-16 by Gregory A. Waller, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Larry Richards - African American Films through 1959 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Film Newspaper Articles, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Limiting the Theatres of Washington D.C, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Photocopy - A October, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "The Seeming Counterfeit" Racial Politics and Early Blackface Mintrelsy, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Reinstating Corporeality: Feminism and Body Politics, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Women Writing the Body let's Watch A Little How She Dances, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Cruising Around the Historical Bolc: Post Modern and popular music in East Los Angeles, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Articles, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - The Effect of Mental Illness on the Families of Six Negro Patitents and Discriminatory Practices, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Black Journals of the U.S - Walter C. Daniel, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - George Schuyler - "Keeping the Negro in his Place", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - The Last Negro - Darryl Plackney, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Martha J Cutter and David Chinitz Articles, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "Colored; Cold. Wrong Somewhere", undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - The Negro Woman's World, 1935-02 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Pulse Magazine, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - DC Census Statistics, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous DC Newspapers/Newsletters, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Colored Library, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Dance Articles Post 1960, 1965-1993 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Report of the Commission of DC 1929, 1931, 1943, 1948, 1929-1948 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Jules Prown Methodology, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Peaceful integration: The Owners Adoption of His Slaves' Food, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Jefferson Building Photo, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Dedication of the Black Press Archives and Gallery of Distinguished Newspaper Publishers, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Moorland- Spingarn Photo Essay/Bios/Micro Film List, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - The Twentieth Century Union League Directory, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Flashback - Gordon Parks and the Image of the Capital City, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Anatomy of the Promenade: The Poltiics of Bourgeois Sociablity in nineteenth-century New York, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Roebuck Sears, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Soul: Black Power, Politics and Pleasure, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - The Finest Outside the Loop: Motion Picture Exhibition in Chicago's Black Metropolis - 1905-1928, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Patterns of Segregation, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - "Every woman is interested in this", undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - News from the Great Wide World:Duke Ellington Count Basie and Black Popular Music 1927-1943, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Embodying Difference: Issues in Dance and Cultural Studies, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Jacqu Malone - Steppin' on the Blues Chapter and Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Population/Census Data, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Crime in the Nation's Capital, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Policies and Actions of Board of Library Trustees, 1896-1994 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Liber Anni - 1943 Dunbar High School (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - A Sociological Look into the Negro Pictorial, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Outstanding Negro Newspapers, Reiteration and Detail, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - The Role of the Press, Radio, and Motion Picture and Negro Morale, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Negro Magazines Come of Age, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - 7th Annual Report - Board of Trustees and 6th Annual Report of the Librarian of the Public Library, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - "Five Years of Progress" DC Recreation board - 1942-1947, undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Notes on the Balinese Cock Fight, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - History and Play: Johan Huizinga and His Critics, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - The Critic, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - The New Municipal Public Library at Washington, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Negro Population - Bureau of the Census, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - The Junior High School Review, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Where is the Negro's Heaven, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - The Messenger - 1927 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Negro Book Club's Guide to African American Book, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Chicago: A Cross-Section of Negro Life, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Hovels or Homes, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Theatres - DC, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Movies/Film Primary Articles, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Dance Narratives and Fantasies of Achievement, undated (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Lets Watch a little how he dances - performing cultural studies, undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - The Skies of Consciousness: African Dance at Pinster in New York 1750-1840, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Library of Congress Catalog, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - The Play of Slave Children in the Plantation Communities of the Old South 1820-1860, undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - The Beginnings of Organized Play for black America: E.T Attwell and the PRAA, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - National Zoo - 1950s/1960s, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - An American Dilemma, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - How the Farmer Can Save his Sweet Potatoes, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Andrew Jackson Middle School Honor Roll Assembly, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Interview with Ann Barnett, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - 12 October 2000 Newspaper Research at MLK, undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - American Library Association Archives Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Search Request - Sterling Online Category, undated (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Eloise Glynn Little Greenfield I'm Born, undated (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Encyclopedia of African American Culture and History, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Contested Terrain, undated (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Miscellaneous Articles/Newspaper Clippings, 1915-1937 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - National Conference on Prevention and Control of Juvenile Delinquency, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Articles "Negro History" Alain Locke/James Baldwin/etc., 1904-1925 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Vegetarian Society Pamphlets (1:3), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Vegetarian Society Pamphlets (2:3), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Vegetarian Society Pamphlets (3:3), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Exhibit Materials Vegetarian Society, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Exhibit Materials Vegetarian Society, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Vegetarian Society Newsletters and Pamphlets, 1997-2002 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Vegetarian Academic Articles, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Eat Smart Program Budget, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Vegetarian Festival Documents, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Vegetarian Correspondence, 2000-2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Spirituality and Vegan Lecture, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Letters of Praise, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Master Thesis "Rethinking Meat", 2001 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Magazines, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Lecture Notes, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Newsday New York City, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Photographs, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Vegetarian Handouts, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Vegetarian Handouts, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1920s-1950s (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Media Write-Up, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Receipts, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Vegeterian Resources, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Vegeterian Society Notes, 2000-2002 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Oral History, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Vegeterian Food and Nut Company, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - PETA Materials, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1890-1950 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - "Blackvegetarians.com", 2003 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Articles, 1945-2002 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Research, 1972-2003 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Advertisements, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Magazines, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Activism, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlets, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Media and Public Relations, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Handouts, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Vegetarian Starter Kit, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Vegetarian Society News, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Herbal Remedies, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Photos and Scanning, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "Meatout", 2002 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - "Turning Point Project", undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Lecture Transparency, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Meyer Foundation, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Vegeterian Websites, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - "Living Foods Diet", undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Website Information, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Collards Photograph, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Notebook, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Photographs, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Boris Article, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Lipsitz Article, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Articles, 1929-1945 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Lubiano Article, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Smith Article, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Archival Material, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - National Negro Market, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - DCPL Monthly Bulletin, 1903-1962 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Washinton Tribune, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Employment Letter, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Leisure Articles, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - The New Philadelphia Story: A Survey of America's 3rd largest Negro Market, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sports - DC General History, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - James Frederick Murphy - Egalitarianism and Separatism, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Buying habits of Negro Families in Pittsburgh's Courierville, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Research Trip to New York, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - VSDC Exhibit, 1905-2002 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Things to do/Schedules/Doctoral Defense Info, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlets - Brochures Handouts Magazines ( 1 of 4), undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Pamphlets - Brochures Handouts Magazines ( 2 of 4), undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Pamphlets - Brochures Handouts Magazines ( 3 of 4), undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Pamphlets - Brochures Handouts Magazines ( 4 of 4), undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Generation of Cooking Celebrating Woman's Day, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 16th Annual Meeting National Consortium on Racial and Ethnic Fairness in the Courts ( 1 of 4), 2004 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 16th Annual Meeting National Consortium on Racial and Ethnic Fairness in the Courts ( 2 of 4), 2004 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 16th Annual Meeting National Consortium on Racial and Ethnic Fairness in the Courts ( 3 of 4), 2004 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 16th Annual Meeting National Consortium on Racial and Ethnic Fairness in the Courts ( 4 of 4), 2004 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - The Sidwell Friends - Cookbook, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Visual images of DC, 1937-1943 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Sports - Jack Johnson, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - U Street PMMAY Materials, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - The Playgoer: A Magazine in the Theatre, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - DC Manuscript Notes, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Associates in Negro Folk Education/Bronze Booklets, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Seventh Day Adventists/Vegetarianism Bibliography History, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Health Status on Negro Workers Masters Thesis, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Health Articles, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - DC Recreation, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - DC Department Stores, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - The History Channel Save Our History Program, 2004-2005 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - First Issues of Magazines ( 1 of 3), 1900-1945 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - First Issues of Magazines ( 2 of 3), 1900-1945 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - First Issues of Magazines ( 3 of 3), 1900-1945 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Biographical Material, 1947-2004 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Pulse, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Our Cause is Marching On: Parent Activism, Browne Junior High School, and the Multiple Meanings of Equality in Post-War Washington, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Afro American Newspaper Articles, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Court Case Info, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Washingtoniana MLK Library Clippings, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Not Crucial to Article, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Edith Portal, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - The Color Line in Public Schools, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - DC Appropriations for,1951, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Beyond Black White and Brown, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1882-1885 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - NYU Alumni Newsletter, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - A Brief Comprehensive Report on the Public Educational Facilities for Colored Children in the District of Columbia, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Misc Correspondence and Washington Post Article on Segregated Schools, 1950-2004 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Public Schools, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Campbell African Methodist Episcopal Church, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Civil Dockets, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Essay Drafts/Outlines, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Public Schools, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Garnet C. Wilkinson, 1938-1962 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bibliography/Notes, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Contacts - Conversations and Interviews, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Playgrounds, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Jumna Archives, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Campbell AME Church, 1947-1969 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Public Schools, 1950-1954 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Misc Articles, 1990-2004 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - HSWDC: notes - C. Welch Papers - Hayes Papers, 1997-2004 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Langston Branch Library, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Marian Anderson Protest Committee, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Birney Elementary School, 1941-1978 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Dual High School, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - DC Federation of Civic Associations, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Kingman Park, 1931-1940 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Images, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Notes/Contracts/Correspondence, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Nellie Venture Greene, 1983-2004 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Journal of Negro Education, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Carnegie Melon Dissertation Multiculturalism, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Public School Buildings - Past and Present, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Parent Activism Draft, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Court Cases - Misc. Wall v Oyster; Brown cases to news, 1910-1948 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Consolidated Parent Group, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Kaila Jalanza, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Baltimore Afro American, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Articles and Archive Info on Women, 1985-2000 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Scholarly Articles and Archive Materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Archival Images, undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Negro Market Articles, 1930-1940 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Robert Weems - Desegregating the Dollar, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Hecht Co., 1896-1998 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Black Performances Working Group, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Secondary Articles on D.C, 1983-1990 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Jones Memorial, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Boiling V. Sharpe, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Gardner Bishop, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Public Schools, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Board of Education, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Marya McQuirter Article, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - BVB Articles, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - DC Public School History, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Journal of Negro Education, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Dissertation Materials, 1940-2000 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "Afro-American", 1949 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Dissertation Draft, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Special Collections Material, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - NAACP, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Education Articles, 1940-1950 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Education Articles, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Moorland Research, 1930-1950 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - ProQuest Materials, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - McQuirter Article, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Submission Guidelines, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - DC Education Legal Cases, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Browne School Documents, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Dissertation Draft, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Eliot Junior High, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - DC Public Schools Oral History, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - News Clippings, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Ranson Papers, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - History of Schools for Negros, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - US Supreme Court Case, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Strike Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Washingtonian, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - McQuirter Article Draft, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Kluger Article, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Howard Law Journal, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - The Education Review, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1943 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Archival Materials and Scholarly Articles, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Chapter 4 Dissertation, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Segregation in Washington - 1948 Report, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Lansburgh's, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Garfunkle's Chapter 5, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 7)